<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ITE393 Exam</string>
    <string name="l">Login</string>
    <string name="Map">Campus Map</string>
    <string name="Back">BACK</string>

    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="part">Be part of our growing community!</string>
    <string name="par2">Choose PHINMA Education</string>

    <string name="part3">As an innovative Philippine business institution, PHINMA believes that access to quality education is the solution to many of our country’s problems. While the enrollment rate in the Philippines has always been high, PHINMA discovered that most students do not finish tertiary education. Students were willing to learn but did not have the resources to stay in school.</string>
    <string name="hp">Home Page</string>
    <string name="c">CITE</string>
    <string name="ca">CAHS</string>
    <string name="ce">CEA</string>
    <string name="be">BELA</string>
    <string name="jp">JPIA</string>
    <string name="tm">TM</string>
    <string name="cma">CMA</string>


    <string name="mods_1">Most importantly, our education is affordable. We do not charge any hidden or unnecessary fees.</string>
    <string name="mods_3">Check our complete list of scholarships below:</string>
    <string name="mods_2">We support deserving students throughout their tertiary learning years by offering scholarship programs. Our Hawak Kamay Scholarship Program provides 50% to 75% discount on tuition and miscellaneous fees for our more financially-challenged students.</string>


    <string name="pin_1">1. PHINMA Scholarship (formerly Presidential Scholarship)</string>


    <string name="citetxt">Bachelor of Science in Computer Science</string>
    <string name="citeTXT">The Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (BS Computer Science) is a dynamic program providing essential knowledge and skills in areas like algorithms, programming, and artificial intelligence. Through a mix of theory and hands-on projects, students develop problem-solving abilities. Graduates are well-prepared for diverse careers in software development, data science, and cybersecurity, positioning them at the forefront of technological innovation.</string>


    <string name="cahstxt">Bachelor of Science in Medical Laboratory Science</string>
    <string name="cahsTXT">The Bachelor of Science in Medical Laboratory Science is a four-year program that provides knowledge in the fields of Clinical Chemistry, Hematology, Microbiology, Immunohematology, Immunology and Serology, Urinalysis, Clinical Microscopy, Parasitology, Cytology, and Histopathology. During their fourth year, students undergo an internship program in a CHED-accredited training laboratory where they rotate between sections. Graduates of the program must take the board exams conducted by the Professional Regulation Commission to qualify as registered medical technologists.</string>


    <string name="cea_BSA_txt">Bachelor of Science in Architecture</string>
    <string name="bsa_TXT">The Bachelor of Architecture program is a comprehensive and innovative course designed to cultivate the skills, knowledge, and creative vision necessary for a successful career in architecture. Our curriculum seamlessly integrates theoretical principles with hands-on design projects, providing students with a solid foundation in architectural theory, history, and technical expertise. Through studio-based learning and real-world applications, students develop the ability to conceptualize and bring to life architectural designs that are both aesthetically compelling and functionally sound. Graduates of our program are well-prepared to embark on diverse career paths in architecture, urban planning, sustainable design, and other related fields, contributing to the built environment with ingenuity and expertise.</string>

    <string name="cea_BSCE_txt">Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering</string>
    <string name="ce_TXT">The Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering program is a four-year course that teaches students the knowledge, skills, and training necessary for designing, constructing and maintaining buildings, and public infrastructure and facilities. We also develop their zest for excellence and lifelong training necessary for adapting to civil engineering trends. Graduates of the BS Civil Engineering program must take the board exams conducted by the Professional Regulation Commission to become professionals.</string>


    <string name="cma_SA_txt">Bachelor of Science in Accountancy</string>
    <string name="SA_TXT">The Bachelor of Science in Accountancy program is a four-year course that prepares students for a professional career in Accountancy, particularly in Public Accounting. The program aims to guide students by providing them technical knowledge, skills and abilities required in the accountancy profession. We also help them develop the values of integrity, independence and skepticism necessary for making professional judgments. Our program uses a competency framework for professional accountants from the International Federation of Accountants, so that graduates may take certifications in Accountancy by the Philippine Professional Regulatory Commission and other international certifying bodies.</string>

    <string name="cma_AT_txt">Bachelor of Science in Accounting Technology</string>
    <string name="AT_THXT">The Bachelor of Science in Accounting Technology program focuses on cultivating the technical expertise, skills, and values essential for a thriving career in accounting management. Our curriculum is meticulously crafted to furnish students with a robust grounding in accounting principles, financial analysis, cost management, and strategic decision-making. Upon completion, our graduates are adeptly equipped</string>

    <string name="cma_TM_txt">Bachelor of Science in Tourism Management</string>
    <string name="TM_TXT">The Bachelor of Science in Tourism Management trains students in a diverse set of skills necessary for their future careers. We use the active learning methodology in honing students’ skills in functional areas like Front Office, Events Planning, Cruise Line Operations, and Travel and Tours. We develop their communication skills so they can properly guide guests through destinations and address their needs and concerns. We also teach our students the values of cultural diversity, sensitivity and versatility needed in touring guests from different cultures. Most importantly, we instill within them the value of our heritage and culture, so that they may best represent the country as our ambassadors. Our program provides students the chance to earn local and international certifications and diplomas (TESDA, American Hospitality and Lodging Education Institute, School D’ Hospitality of Singapore) for prestigious local and global employment opportunities.</string>

    <string name="cma_ENTREP_txt">Bachelor of Science in Entrepreneurship</string>
    <string name="entrep_txt">The Bachelor of Science in Entrepreneurship (BS Entrepreneurship) is a dynamic program that equips students with essential knowledge and skills for success in entrepreneurship. The curriculum integrates theory with hands-on experience, covering business planning, financial management, marketing, and innovation. Through real-world projects, graduates emerge ready to identify opportunities, create sustainable business models, and navigate the challenges of entrepreneurship. The program fosters creativity and resilience, preparing students to excel as business leaders and innovators.</string>


    <string name="hp2">Making Lives Better Through Education</string>
    <string name="about5">PHINMA Education is under the PHINMA Group of Companies, the first Filipino-managed investment firm.</string>
    <string name="about4">For more than a decade, PHINMA built its reputation on transforming existing educational institutions to better serve Filipino students. PHINMA Education begins this process by strategically selecting a school from a key growth area and thoroughly transforming its academics, operations, and student community in order to ensure success for Filipino youth coming from low-income families.</string>
    <string name="about3">Overall enrollment figures in the country have always been high. Despite this, attrition rates remained high and consistent. Out of four students who enter first grade, only one will go on to finish a tertiary degree. Learning about these statistics led PHINMA’s leaders to realize that they could fulfill their mission by helping improve the country’s state of education. With this in mind, they entered the education field to introduce reforms and innovations. In 2004, PHINMA Education was born.</string>
    <string name="about2">PHINMA Education seeks to provide quality tertiary education to underserved Filipino youth. Our various learning strategies and interventions equip our students with professional and core work skills to attain gainful employment, whether or not they graduate. By knowing who our students are and where they come from, we are able to tailor our programs to what they want to achieve.</string>
    <string name="about1">For more than a decade, PHINMA built its reputation on transforming existing educational institutions to better serve Filipino students. PHINMA Education begins this process by strategically selecting a school from a key growth area and thoroughly transforming its academics, operations, and student community in order to ensure success for Filipino youth coming from low-income families.</string>
    <string name="scholarships">Scholarships</string>
    <string name="benefits">Benefits:</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="the_bachelor_of_science_in_entrepreneurship_bs_entrepreneurship_is_a_dynamic_program_that_equips_students_with_essential_knowledge_and_skills_for_success_in_entrepreneurship_the_curriculum_integrates_theory_with_hands_on_experience_covering_business_planning_financial_management_marketing_and_innovation_through_real_world_projects_graduates_emerge_ready_to_identify_opportunities_create_sustainable_business_models_and_navigate_the_challenges_of_entrepreneurship_the_program_fosters_creativity_and_resilience_preparing_students_to_excel_as_business_leaders_and_innovators">The Bachelor of Science in Entrepreneurship (BS Entrepreneurship) is a dynamic program that equips students with essential knowledge and skills for success in entrepreneurship. The curriculum integrates theory with hands-on experience, covering business planning, financial management, marketing, and innovation. Through real-world projects, graduates emerge ready to identify opportunities, create sustainable business models, and navigate the challenges of entrepreneurship. The program fosters creativity and resilience, preparing students to excel as business leaders and innovators.</string>


    <string name="phinmahandbook">The PHINMA Education Network (PEN) Student Handbook, Teriany Level consists of various policies which govern tertiary level students of the School. In addition, we are also including here such matters as: the schools mission and vision, a short history and background of the school, and some information on the PHINMA Education Network and PHINMA.</string>
    <string name="phinma1">The PEN student is expected to take responsibility for reading and understanding the contents of this Handbook. When in doubt about the understanding of the policies, he should approach the school officials concerned and ask for clarification.</string>
    <string name="phinma2">The information found in this Handbook may be revised or expanded to
    conform to changes that may occur in the School. Additional policies or
    amendments may be issued by the PEN Administrative Council from time to
        time through appropriate memoranda and announcements.</string>
    <string name="phinma3">Welcome to the
PHINMA Education Network</string>
    <string name="phinma4">Welcome to the PHINMA Education Network!
Your entry to this PHINMA Education Network (PEN)school ushers you likewise into a group with over 40 years of service in professional management. </string>
    <string name="phinma5">As a student of the School you are expected to meet certain standards of
academic performance. You are likewise expected to adhere to prescribed
norms and behavioral standards and values as described in the rules and
regulations and policies of the School. </string>
    <string name="phinma6">In the School you will meet men and women who are competent in the areas
in which they are assigned. Their duty is to help you realize your right to quality
education. </string>
    <string name="phinma7">We hope your stay in the PHINMA Group will be a meaningful growth
experience for you. Just as we have seen many of our students work hard to
learn and develop their character, so do we also wish to see you exert your best
during your stay in the School. </string>
    <string name="phinma8">Again, welcome and congratulations! You are now a member of the PHINMA
Education Network. </string>
    <string name="phinma9">Mission and Vision </string>
    <string name="phinma10">Mission of the PHINMA Education Network
 </string>
    <string name="phinma11">Through the application of effective management in institutions of higher and
basic learning, to give Filipinos better access to affordable, high quality
education in key cities throughout the Philippines, preparing them to be globally
competitive. </string>
    <string name="phinma12">School Mission </string>
    <string name="phinma13">To develop the Filipino youth into employable global professionals through the
endowment of knowledge and skills and the formation of character and spirit. </string>
    <string name="phinma14">School Vision
 </string>
    <string name="phinma15">With distinct advantage in English Communication and Information Technology,
to be the leading institution of higher learning in the region in the development
of globally competitive professionals. </string>
    <string name="phinma16"> Academic Policies</string>
    <string name="phinma17">A. Grading System </string>
    <string name="phinma18">The grading system will be provided to the students by their respective
teachers through the syllabus. If understanding of the system is not clear, it is the
responsibility of the student to seek clarification from his/her teacher, program
head or dean. </string>
    <string name="phinma19">Grades are given out in numerical format. A student who has passed the
subject will receive any of the following grades: 1.00, 1.25, 1.50, 1.75, 2.00,
2.25, 2.50, 2.75, or 3.00. The grade of 1.00 is the highest possible grade that a student may get. A student who has failed the subject will receive a grade of 5.00. </string>
    <string name="phinma20">A student may also get a grade other than those specified earlier.
These grades may be given for various reasons such as, but not limited to:
incompleteness of submitted requirements, withdrawal from a subject - with
permission, withdrawal from a subject - without permission, failure due to
absences, no examination because the student was not able to obtain an exam
permit.
 </string>
    <string name="phinma21">B. Release of Grades </string>
    <string name="phinma22">Final grades will be released by the Office of the Registrar. Other term exams
will be released by the faculty. </string>
    <string name="phinma23">C. Incomplete Grade </string>
    <string name="phinma24">A student who gets an incomplete grade has two consecutive terms to complete
it. The Dean/Director must have approved the granting of the incomplete grade.
Failure to get a passing grade for an incomplete grade after two terms has elapsed
means that the student will get a failing mark in the subject concerned.
The corresponding completion fee shall be applied. </string>
    <string name="phinma25">D. Academic Probation
 </string>
    <string name="phinma26">A student who incurs failing grades in three (3) subjects of his academic load
in a semester will be accepted on probation the following semester and the student
will only be allowed to carry a maximum load of 18 units. Should the student fail
in two (2) subjects during the probationary period, a maximum load of 12 units shal
be enforced. The student may assume a regular load only when the mentioned 12
units have been passed. </string>
    <string name="phinma27">E. Class Attendance </string>
    <string name="phinma28">1. Every student is required to attend his classes regularly and punctually. Absence
or persistent tardiness for more than 20% of the total number of class meetings (one
hour for each meeting) during the entire course in any particular subject shall be
sufficient reason for disqualifying a student from taking final examinations or for
dropping the student without credit. The same shall apply if a student has incurred: </string>
    <string name="phinma29">more than 3 absences in a 1-unit subject
more than 5 absences in a 2-unit subject
more than 8 absences in a 3-unit subject
more than 11 absences in a 4-unit subject
more than 14 absences in a 5-unit subject
more than 17 absences in a 6-unit subject </string>
    <string name="phinma30">2. A student who is late for class for at least 10 minutes will be marked as absent. </string>
    <string name="phinma31">3. A student will incur an absence for every 3 times that he is tardy. </string>
    <string name="phinma32">4. The teacher concerned must account for all absences in his subjects. </string>
    <string name="phinma33">5. The teacher must report to the College Dean/Director students who have beenabsent for 3 consecutive class meetings. Succeeding absences of students must bereported to the Guidance Counselor. </string>
    <string name="phinma34">6. No excuse for an absentee or absences will be considered valid unless the studentcan show that his absences were unavoidable or necessary. </string>
    <string name="phinma35">7. In case of an absence due to sickness, the student must present a written notefrom parent/guardian or certificate from an attending physician stating the natureof the sickness. </string>
    <string name="phinma36">F.    Promotion and Retention
 </string>
    <string name="phinma37">Promotion and retention policies will be provided to the students by their respectivecolleges. If understanding of the policies is not clear, it is the responsibility of thestudent to seek clarification from the college to which he belongs. </string>
    <string-array name="campus">
        <item>PHINMA University of Pangasinan</item>
        <item>PHINMA Araullo University</item>
        <item>PHINMA Saint Jude collge</item>
        <item>PHINMA Cagayan De Oro College</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="gender">
        <item>Male</item>
        <item>Female</item>
        <item>Other</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="college">
        <item>CITE</item>
        <item>CAHS</item>
        <item>CEA</item>
        <item>BELA</item>
        <item>CMA</item>
        <item>CCJ</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="course">
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Computer Science</item>
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Medical Laboratory Science</item>
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering</item>
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Architecture</item>
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Tourism Management</item>
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Entrepreneurship</item>
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Accountancy </item>
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Accounting Information System</item>
        <item>Bachelor of Arts in English Language Studies</item>
        <item>Bachelor of Science in Criminology.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="years">
        <item>2025</item>
        <item>2024</item>
        <item>2023</item>
        <item>2022</item>
        <item>2021</item>
        <item>2020</item>
        <item>2019</item>
        <item>2018</item>
        <item>2017</item>
        <item>2016</item>
        <item>2015</item>
        <item>2014</item>
        <item>2013</item>
        <item>2012</item>
        <item>2011</item>
        <item>2010</item>
        <item>2009</item>
        <item>2008</item>
        <item>2007</item>
        <item>2006</item>
        <item>2005</item>
        <item>2004</item>
        <item>2003</item>
        <item>2002</item>
        <item>2001</item>
        <item>2000</item>
        <item>1999</item>
        <item>1998</item>
        <item>1997</item>
        <item>1996</item>
        <item>1995</item>
        <item>1994</item>
        <item>1993</item>
        <item>1992</item>
        <item>1991</item>
        <item>1990</item>
        <item>1989</item>
        <item>1988</item>
        <item>1987</item>
        <item>1986</item>
        <item>1985</item>
        <item>1984</item>
        <item>1983</item>
        <item>1982</item>
        <item>1981</item>
        <item>1980</item>
        <item>1979</item>
        <item>1978</item>
        <item>1977</item>
        <item>1976</item>
        <item>1975</item>
        <item>1974</item>
        <item>1973</item>
        <item>1972</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="days">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>13</item>
        <item>14</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>16</item>
        <item>17</item>
        <item>18</item>
        <item>19</item>
        <item>20</item>
        <item>21</item>
        <item>22</item>
        <item>23</item>
        <item>24</item>
        <item>25</item>
        <item>26</item>
        <item>27</item>
        <item>28</item>
        <item>29</item>
        <item>30</item>
        <item>31</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="month">
        <item>January</item>
        <item>February</item>
        <item>March</item>
        <item>April</item>
        <item>May</item>
        <item>June</item>
        <item>July</item>
        <item>August</item>
        <item>September</item>
        <item>October</item>
        <item>November</item>
        <item>December</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>